Hi, everyone.
So in this lesson, we are going to learn what are two dimensional arrays?
So consider, for example, you want to implement boardgame, so let us consider that you want to implement
tic tac toe game.
So in tic tac toe.
We have a basically two dimensional, Larry, and basically there are three rules and three columns.
So this matrix has a dimension of three corsetry.
Now, with the current knowledge that we have, how can we store tic tac toe?
So basically, the first option is with the use of three one damisch, Larry, so I will create three
areas.
So even a two and three.
So even will correspond to the first row, U2 is going to correspond for the second and it is for the
third row of the tic tac toe.
So this even will store the data president in the first year to store the data presented in the second
row, and it will show the data presented in the third row.
So, for example, if you do something here, if you are going to store something here, then that data
will be stored.
At this point, if you want to store something at this location.
So you have to go to edit three and add zero next year.
Saw the data.
So this is the first option.
But this option is not very good.
Why this is not very good because suppose you want to implement a chess game.
So in chess you have eight Crossett So basically you have to take it one day.
So even to eight.
So I have to take it one day at a one dimensional Larry.
So this first option is not a very good option.
Now, the second option for implementing tic tac toe, what can I do?
So in total, I have nine cells.
So what I will do, I will create a one.
Deery And in this one I will basically have.
So this one, there will be a size nine.
So the next will be zero and the last index is going to be eight.
Now, for example, if you want to insert something at this location, so if you do the indexing so
zero one, do you remember the indexing always starts on zero.
So this is 012.
Now, what I want to do, I want to store something at this location.
So it's rule number two and it indexes one.
So I want to store something at this location, TUCUMÃN and what this location will be in this area.
So basically, if you count.
So one, two, three, four, five, six, seven and eight.
So its location will be seven.
So you will store whatever you are going to store at this location that will be stored at a Nexus seven
corresponding to this one, that.
So this is our second option of implementing the tic tac toe again.
So the problem with this approach is basically you have to calculate, you have to do some calculation
to find out the index in the.
But the third option of implementing tic tac toe is with the help of to damage Hillary's.
So now let us see what are to them.
So, as the name suggests, there will be two dimensions, just like three Grasstree.
So basically there are two dimensions in chess.
We have two dimensions, eight closet.
So now let's see how we will create our two damisch Larry.
So, for example, if you want to create an area, what you will write.
You will read it if you want to create a different picture than the name of the ad and then let's say
I want Lente five, so what will happen?
You will get an ad, the first index is going to be zero and the last index is going to be four.
Now, if you want to create a two dimensional activity.
All right.
So I want to create the area of integers.
So I will give the data type then the name of the array.
So I want to be to the name of that is B now you have to give two things.
So here the ad is a one dimensional, so you just have to give the lente.
But the good Michelet is.
So there are two damage.
And first I have rules and I have columns.
So what I will do, I will write like this.
One box and second box, so this first box will contain how many rules and the second box will contain
how many columns.
So for example, if I give three of my four, three and four and so what will be my duty metrics?
So I will have three rows and I will have four columns.
So this is the number of rules.
So three rules.
So these are the rules and I want four columns, so this is the first column, the second column, third
and fourth column, and we know the indexing in the area starts from zero.
So similarly, the indexing will start from zero to zero.
One, two, three.
I have four columns and zero one two.
So I have three rows.
So what is the lasting next lasting Nix's basically to comadre, what is the first index?
So first index zero zero.
So now let's say if you want to take input, so how can you take input?
So in Eddie.
If you want to take input, so what we have to do, I will write how many elements you want to insert,
then I will take the number of elements.
And then basically you have to choose a follow up starting from Zero and I in and I plus plus.
And then you will do something like this in each of these, the name of the area.
So for taking the input from the user, we have to do this thing.
Now let's see how we can take input into the Matrix and Two-dimensional area.
So let's see.
So there are two ways of taking input.
So what is the first option?
So the first option is basically take input throughways.
And the second option is basically they can put calombaris.
So what is the meaning of always so it always is very common and we will use this only.
So it always means taking part for the 08 role, then taking part for the first two, then taking part
for the second.
First of all, I have to do I will take how many rules and how many columns.
So for these two, the first step is going to be same.
You will create a truly matrix.
So let's set number of rules.
That hundred number of columns are also 100.
Then you will take two variables, four rows and columns.
So let's call them Immonen.
Then you will take how many rules and they will take how many columns.
So here M signifies rules.
And it's basically the number of columns, so the first step is going to be very simple, just like
we used to take.
And here he will take two variables, number of rules and number of columns.
Now the defense will come that you are going to take input railways or column ways.
So let's say if the value of em is, let's say three and and is two, so basically ridiculous situation.
So I'm going to have three rows and only two columns.
So three rows and two columns.
So this is a situation, this is 012 and this is zero and one now let's talk about railways in port.
So if you want to take in Butros, let's take input for the name of the name of the two reraise.
So first you will take the input four 00.
You will write a scene.
Zero zero, then you will write zero one.
Then you will write one zero.
So this is for the first rule, first rule has been over.
Now I'm taking input for Secondo and Indexes one.
So since the first column, this is the second column then.
So then I will take the input for this.
Now take the input for the third row.
So you will write.
So this indexes to zero, so to zero.
And this one is actually two one.
So you will write to one.
And again, since.
So this is taking input railway's, I am taking input Detroit, similarly, you can do the opposite
if you want to take input Calloway's.
What you can do first will first take the input for this will then take the input for this.
So Calombaris is very similar to the railways.
So for now, let us concentrate on railways, because everyone uses railways is more popular.
So if you want to take on board roadways.
What could we have to right, so if you can see.
What we are doing here, so I need to loops, I'm going to take in waterwise, so I need to loop so
one loop for iterating over the rules and second loop for ideating over the columns.
Simple, I'm repeating myself.
I want to take and throughways.
So I need to loop one loop related over the rules and when Loop will, I tripped over the columns simple.
And what we have to do so for each rule, for each rule, I have to take input for all the columns.
Similarly, for the second row, I will take input for all the columns.
Similarly, for the third row, I will take input for the third column for the forward through.
I will take input for the fourth column.
Do loops will be there.
So the outermost loop will iterate over the rules.
So let's say I equals zero.
Number of rules are.
So I listed him and I placeless.
So this is the loop for iterating over the rules now for each rule.
I have to I read all the columns, so one loop inside this big loop.
So this is for real.
So this loop is going to get rid of the rules.
And we know that for each rule, I have to take the input for all the columns.
So let's take a variable.
So, Jake Lizardo, how many columns are there.
So there are and columns so less than N g plus.
Plus and again the syntax is very simple, syntax is very simple in there.
Now that is B and I will write A through and git column.
Simple.
Etcetera, etcetera.
You can see I used the Rule and Giat column, so just the column.
So this is the way I will take input from the user in that I use to take input like this.
I call zero I list and then I placeless.
And I used to write Sini of I.
So the idea is very similar.
Here I was just reading over the area because the area was one dimensional, but here we have two dimensions.
Since we have two dimensions, then it is obvious that we need two loops.
So this is the outer loop and this one is the inner loop.
Again, very simple.
First, we have to get rid of the rules and for each rule I have to get it or the column because I'm
digging in input railway's.
What will happen?
So this will become outlook and this will become inner loop, just the opposite.
So now let us write the code and let's see how to create a truly matrix.
So let us create a two three matrix so added to that mission, Larry.
Let's say the name of the ADC, the number of rules hundred, and let's say the number of columns,
800.
Now, what they have to do for taking the input from the user, I need to take how many rules and how
many columns to give me how many rules and give me how many columns.
Now I am digging in, but always so I need one loop, I tripped over the rules.
So am I reading all the rules and now I need one loop for iterating over the columns.
So for each rule I have to I wrote the column so I equals.
So we have to take another variable.
So J equals zero G less than N and plus plus.
And then I will take scene if I I get through and get column, so this is exactly the same as we discussed
here.
Exactly same color.
So what I'm doing here, I am getting older and for each rule I am editing over the column.
Then take the input.
I throw and get column.
So let us try to run our program and let's see everything is working fine or not.
So first, I have to give the value of Immonen, so let's say.
I want tutus and three columns now it is waiting for my input.
So how many elements I have to give two to try to cross three.
So I have to give six elements selected.
The elements are one, two, three, four, five and six and press enter.
So basically, our code is working fine.
Our code is properly taking our input.
Now for this for this input, what will be our matrix?
So our matrix is going to be very simple.
So you give the value of so you give em equals two and you give an equal three and then you give six
entries.
So one, two, three, four, five, six.
So if you will draw the metrics, it will draw you to the missionary.
You need to lose.
So to lose and you need three columns.
So three columns and then you give six entries.
One, two, three, four, five and six.
This is to include three metrics, this is zero one and two, this is zero and one.
So this is the input.
Now, let us try to print this metrics.
So I want to print this metrics and I want to see.
How mathematics look like, so again, we have two options.
So first is to always paint the matrix, so print the first rule, if you will print the first one,
two, three.
Now print the second.
So four, five, six.
And the second option is let's print the column.
It's just like digging in.
But we can also print columns, for example, print the first column.
So it will be one for now print the second column, so it will be two five now print the third column,
so it will be three six.
So let's print it always.
And then we will also print the calombaris.
So for printing it always.
If I want to print throughways, how Will opened again, just like taking input, what do we do?
We will need to loop's what I want to do.
So for each row, for each row, I will add to do the column and I will print the content.
Similarly for the next row ovulated order column and I will print the content.
So I need two loops.
So the first loop is going to read over the rules.
So I equals zero.
I list them and I placeless and for each row what we have to do, we have to print the content.
So for printing the content, I have to iterate over the columns, which equals Ruggie less than angioplasties
and print the content to.
Then if that is B, I want to print I and column now after printing the rule.
So after printing the rule.
After printing the rule, I have to go to the next.
So for going to the next row I will write code and line.
Simple, so let us bring our mattocks throughways.
So this line is basically for going to the next room, simple, so we will give this input.
And let us bring to Royce, so let's see.
So overprinting Roys, let me right here I am branding always, and this is also always so we can just
copy the code copied and pasted here.
So what we are doing, instead of seeing what I will write, I will write code Miskelly.
We are printing the content and after printing Vendel, so for going to the next room you will write
code and line and that's all.
So this is always print.
So I have basically two rows and three columns and I have to give six elements, so the elements are
one, two, three, four, five and six.
And this is so OK, so I didn't give this piece.
So that's why they are printing.
That's why that's why my output is.
Veered, so let's give the space.
So I am giving spaces between the elements now, our output will be in correctly.
Two rows, three columns now, degree of six elements.
One, two, three, four, five and six.
So this is the content of the two dimensional area, always one, two, three and four, five, six.
You can see one, two, three and four, five, six.
So I will call this printing railway's output in the correct manner.
Now, let's try to print calombaris, so if you want to print calombaris, what do you have to do?
Again, very simple, but will do the show for each column.
I have to.
I read all the rules.
Just we will do the opposite.
But I'm saying.
So what was it always?
So the devices I trade all the rules and for each little printed the column.
What Columbus's.
You read over the column and for each column, you will print that simple.
So basically, what will be our court?
So our court will look like this.
First, we have to treat.
Or the columns, so for our trading water column.
So I so I equals zero I.
List and so number of columns that end and I placeless, so I am I over the columns and for each column
I have to write it over the rules.
So remember, her name is Ruth.
And is the number of columns so you can see here rows and columns, similarly, this is columns and.
So am I reading over the rules now for each column, we have to iterate over the rules so J equals zero
G list and M g plus plus I will simply write out the name of the error is B, I want to print it column.
So if you want to print it column.
So I will come here.
And Getrude, so here it was IJI.
But here, what is I.
So this is a and this is G, so G is actually rule and first index.
So so this one, this is actually rule.
And this is Colin.
So here you have to ride first and then I because Jase wrote a column and after printing one column
for going to the next column, you will write out and line.
And so this is printing calombaris.
This is how we will print calombaris simple.
So what should be our output should be one four to five and then three six.
So let me write this code.
So this is a two way sprint.
Now I want to bring to Columbus, so let's spend.
Calombaris, so approach is very simple, we have to tread all the columns so close to zero, I listin
enablers, plus I am irritating all the columns and for each column I have to read over the rules.
So J equals zero.
Similarly, J List and M.G. Placeless.
And then I want to print so the name of the is be the name of that is.
So I want to print my gear through and I get a column and we will give Space's.
Between the elements and after printing the one column for going to the next column, right, she out
and line.
So this is all so this is column wise.
Now, let's see.
Number of Ruza to number of columns are three and the elements are one, two, three, four, five and
six.
So this is a revised print we have seen already, and this is called a misprint.
When four to five and six.
So you can compare.
So you can compare both.
So this is it always just like this one and this is calombaris.
When four to five and six, when four to five to six, so our goal is working 100 percent correct.
So this is the complete cold.
Now, in the next few days, we will discuss how we can initialize our Tooryalai.
I will see you there.
Bye bye.