I have even so in this lesson, we are going to learn how we can initialize our metrics or you can say
to them, gelati.
So how do we initialize our Wendy area, so we write like this and let's say four elements and I will
give four values there to one, two, three and four.
So this is the way for initializing, I wonder now how we can initialize our tutelary, so I will write
like this.
I want to create a truly array of integers, many of the number of rows and columns, let's say two
rows and three columns, and I will initialize it like this.
So I will give one, two and three.
So this is a content one, two and three, so this is the content for the first group.
Now I have to give one more, so then I will write four, five and six.
So that's how I will initialize my to the area.
So this will look like this, I have two rows and three columns.
So in the first row, I will fill this element one, two, three.
In the next room, I will fill these elements four, five and six.
So it is very simple to initialize our Tooryalai now and to create it basically giving rules is optional.
So giving rules is optional and giving columns is mandatory.
So this is giving columns are mandatory and giving the value of rules are optional and we will see why
it is so but not in this video, probably in the next video.
So basically, I can write like this also.
I want to create a tutelary, I do not want to give rules, and again, the columns are mandatory,
so we have to give columns and if I will write like this.
One, two and three.
And let's say in the next room, four, five, four, five, six, and now seven, eight, nine.
OK, so this is not this is only coma.
And then this so be my final edit, so how many troops will be there so we can figure out with the help
of the number of elements that I'm trying to insert so I will have to use and the number of columns
are obviously given three to three rows and three columns.
What is the content of the first trial, it is one, two, three.
What is the content for the second four or five, six, and what is the content for the turtles?
Seven, eight, nine.
So that is the meaning of giving all is optional, giving rules is optional, but giving the number
of columns in it already is mandatory.
Now, let's not tell me what will happen if I try and do something like this.
And we I do not want to give the number of rules, but I want to give the number of columns which are
three.
And what is my content, so let's say one, two.
Now, let's.
Three, four, five.
And now let's see.
Seven and eight.
So what will be my duty, really, so one, two and three.
So first of all, I will have three rules and the number of columns have given three.
So this is three Grasstree.
Trigonometry, what is the content for the first, the content for the first rule is one, two, one
and two.
What is the content for the second or three, four and five?
What is the content for the third row, seven and eight?
And what will happen to the values which are not provided by the user?
So I will put zero there.
So this is just like one.
So in one day, if you will do something like this after and you give only one value, let's say one,
or do you give two values, then what will happen?
So basically you will get.
Four boxes and inside the first two boxes, the values would be one and two and the values will become
zero.
So that is what happening here.
All the values which which I will not provide, they will automatically become zero.
Simple.
So let's take one more example.
So let's see if I will do something like this.
I want to create a truly toread.
Let's say five crews will be there and four columns are going to be presented, and I give value like
this one and two, and then I give three and four.
So what will happen?
So first of all, I'm going to have five crews and they will be four columns.
So first row, second row.
Third, fourth and fifth through.
And this is first column, second column, third and fourth column.
So what is the content for the first rule?
This is one and two, what is the content for the second?
This is three and four.
And what will happen to all the all these black boxes?
So they will become zero.
So zero will be placed everywhere.
So this is the desert.
So I hope you understood.
Now I want to initialize my complete matrix complete to the area with all the zeroes.
So, for example, what I want to say here is.
So how do you create an area with all the zeros, how to initialize an array with all the zeros, so
you will have to write something like this individually?
Let's say you want to create a system, and if you write it like this, then what will happen?
So all the elements inside already.
So first of all, this element is zero.
So that's why the first element will become zero and the rest of the elements are going to become zero.
Now I want to initialize my toread with all the zeros again, the syntax is very simple.
Let certain rules and then columns and you will write it something like this zero.
So what will happen again?
You will get a 10, Gosplan.
Tutelary, so this is zero nine and again, zero nine and all the values inside the studio today will
be zeroes, so zeros will be there.
So that's hope we can initialize our to Matrix with all the zeros simple.
So now let us try to print all this, because I know we should not trust someone.
We should write the code and then we should see what our output will be.
So let's say.
OK, so first of all, let us create a function.
So how do we create a function, so let us create a function print, Eddie.
So this brain function, what it will take.
It will take, obviously, the effort to do damage.
Larry.
It will take how many rules are there and it will take how many columns are there?
Then they have to do so, let's copy this so-called.
I'm going to print the content of the dreary roadways and all of this comment, everything from here.
So what I will do, I will not take the input.
I would just like to call the function so.
Let us initialize already.
So the I do not want to give the number of rules because giving number of rules are optional, I just
want to give the number of columns.
So let's say the number of columns are two.
Correct.
So now let us initialize our address or the first, let's say one to.
Now, let's say I want to give Tecoma for.
So this is going to have to do so, we have to call this function Braintree.
So let's call it a function.
So I have to pass the ADA, so let's pass any sort of way of passing the ADA is exactly the same.
We are passing the ADA just like we used to pass in one Michelet and just the name of the crazy enough.
Then how many rules so there are two rules and there are two columns, so the value of mining in to
commit to.
Correct.
Now one thing, so this court is not correct.
Why?
It is not correct.
Because I told you giving rules are optional, but giving columns are mandatory.
So giving column time and it is all this is the same if you want to pass a Tooryalai, giving columns
are mandatory.
So what I want to say here is just like I told you, that when you are creating to really giving, the
values of rules are optional, but giving the values of columns are mandatory.
Similarly, when you want to pass an added function, so we want to pass a TOORYALAI to a function.
So giving the rules.
So giving the rules are again optional, but giving the number of columns are mandatory while it is
mandatory.
We will see it in the next video.
So this is too.
So that's why you have to right.
To hear.
OK, so let's test our program.
So this is my output went to 2004.
Now, let's do some experiments.
Now, let's say instead of two.
If the number of columns are five, so what should be my output?
So again, if you are making it five, then you have to write five here also because the number of columns
should be seen.
So this value and this value, they should be.
This is the requirement and why this is the requirement.
We will see it in the next video.
So let's run our program.
OK, so one thing that I did wrong here is so the number of columns, actually five.
Now, let's run again.
So now you can see.
So there are Zulu's besant everywhere.
So this will be so when until then, then the content of the second are three and four and then the
all the three rest columns will become zero.
So this is the output.
Correct.
And again, I'm repeating myself, giving the value of columns are mandatory, Vytenis mandatory.
We will see it in the next video.
So you have to five.
So this value and this value they should match.
Otherwise your output will be wrong.
Moeletsi.
Now, let's say the number of are also five is the number of rules at five.
Let's change.
Let's make five here.
So now let's try to test our program.
So thereas you lose Besant everywhere.
So let me explain this output to you.
So, again, there are five rules and five columns, so you will get a five cross, five matrix.
The content of the first rule is to the content of the second rule, and for rest they will be zeros
everywhere.
So zero zero zero.
So that's where you can see how many zeros are there.
And can we initialize our The Matrix with zeroes?
Yes, we definitely we can.
So how will initialise ever truly matics with the rules, so let us create an already let them be.
Number of rules, again, optional.
Let's say there are five rows and five columns.
And I want to initialize my area with all the zeroes, so I will try to zero here simple.
And I will call I will pass very.
So you can see is present everywhere.
So in this video, we learned two important things.
First thing is basically how to initialize our to the Matrix, how to initialize our to the area.
We learned how we can initialize our Tooryalai.
And the second thing is basically when you're initializing the to the array, giving the value of Ruza
optional, but giving the values of columns military similarly when you are passing.
So when you are passing your Tooryalai to a function, then the number of rules, so the value of you
can give rules, but given the value of columns are mandatory.
So when you are passing function, when you are passing to the area to a function, so giving the value
of columns are mandatory.
So this is mandatory.
And the value should be same.
And giving the value of rules are optional.
So this is optional.
Now, the next video, we will discuss why giving the value of condoms are mandatory, so I will see
you in the next one.
Bye bye.