Hi, everyone.
So in this video, we will discuss how to realities are actually stored.
So, for example, if it will create a windy area, let's say five, the size is five.
So what will happen?
So basically you will get five blocks of memory, five blocks of continuous memory, and the size will
be don't debate.
And let's say if we want to take in what we will do, you will create a variable and you will take the
value of N from the user and let's say the value of industry.
So the value of industry, I will use the first three blocks and these two blocks are not used now.
Similarly, let us consider to the idea, for example, if you create a Tooryalai letter to the number
of rules are five and the number of columns are also five.
So what will happen?
You will get five rows and five columns.
So first or second or third row, fourth and fifth row, similarly, first column, second and third,
fourth and fifth column.
And now let's see what I will take.
So I will take the value of rows and columns, input from the user.
So I'm going to create a variable eminent and the user will give me the value of them, which is the
number of rules and which is the number of columns.
Let's say the value of em is three and the value of these.
So what I will do, I will take.
So I will make use of three rows and only two columns.
So only this much part of the judiciary will be used.
So just like this one.
So in this case, I'm using three blocks and in this case I'm using only these three three rows and
two columns.
So this is not actually how my daughter is, Astwood.
So there are two ways of storing my duty.
So first one is actually rule major.
And second one is actually called Amedure.
So, Collum.
Column major, and what is the difference?
So let's say this is one, two, three, four, five.
And then six, seven, eight, nine and 10, so it will be 15, then 20, and then here you will have
25.
So in the room we your form.
So what I will do.
So this is actually five crossway.
So first thing is same between major general media.
What we will have, you will have vendetti.
Basically, this is your salary and it size will be five to five, that is, there will be total twenty
five elements.
So the first index is going to be zero and the last index is going to be 25 24 because there are 25
blocks.
So the last index is going to be drawn before I'm repeating myself.
So this matrix is actually five gross five and how this is actually stored.
So the first step is same for the Mejor.
What they call a major what is happening inside the memory, you will get a one diary, you will get
a continuous block of memory.
Twenty five blocks of continuous memory.
First index is obviously zero.
And the last index is obviously 24 now in the major form.
So so this is so this is, let's say, four major.
And now this is called major.
Again, the size of the area will be the same.
This is your zero index and this is your index 24.
So this is your column, Mejor.
Now, what really happens in the room is what I will do, so I will storm the first row.
So this will be one, two, three, four and five.
Then I will stop the second row, then I will stop the third row.
Then I was told the full truth and finally I will throw the fifth through.
So this will be 25, then 24, then 23 and so on.
Similarly, this will be six, then seven and so on.
So this is all major.
We are starting railway's.
So we are starting railway's first, I'm starting the first row.
Then the second row then stored the third row, then stored the photo and then stored the fifth through.
So this is how room works.
And what Escola Major, you can guess, first stored the first column.
Then stole the second column, so first let us throw the first column, so this will be one, then it
will be six, then it will be 11, then it will be basically 16 and so on.
So first stop, the first column.
Then stole the second column, then stole the third column, so this was his first, this column will
be stored, then this column.
So first this column will be stored, then this column will be stored, then this column, then this
column and finally this column.
So the last five elements will be 25, then 20, then 15, then 10 and then five.
I hope you understood both so Roumeliotis store, Roberto stole the first row, then stole the second
row, then third, then fourth, then fifth and so on.
And in column media, I am going to store column by column.
So first store the first column.
Then he was told the second column, then installed the third column, then install the fourth column
and so on.
Now among these two rule major is actually the correct one.
So we use this rule, Major.
I'm repeating myself.
So this is how we visualize our judiciary.
So this is only for visualisations now inside the memory, inside our system.
This Tuori matrix is actually stored as a one dimensional Larry.
And to store this one dimensionality, basically there are two approaches.
First is the major approach.
Second is the major approach.
So among these two approaches, Romelio approach is used.
So we are going to use ROADM approach and media approach is not used.
It is very rarely used.
All the systems in today's world uses our approach now in the roomier approach.
Let's see how it will work.
So, for example, if you want to store something, let's say my ETA is a, again, five Roosen, five
columns, so you will get fifers.
And you will get five columns, correct, so the first, second, third and fourth and fifth through
similarly first column, second, third, fourth and fifth column.
And now let's say you want to do something like this.
Go to Secondo, you want to do aof to one equals seven, so this is zero, one, two, three and four.
This is zero one, two, three and four.
Now we are going to visualize it like this, but actually it will be stored as a one degree.
So after one.
So this is two and one.
So here I will store seven.
For visualisations, this is correct, but how it will actually be getting.
So basically, again, you will have a one very.
And we are actually going to stay in the room.
So this is index zero, this is index 24.
Now I want to throw this element seven.
So what we have to do, we have to find the index.
So basically, you have to convert the politician to come on in today, one day.
So this is one theory.
So you have to find the correct index for inserting Tucumán.
And how we can find that correct next.
So basically, let's see, so this is to come out when so what we have to do.
So we have to skip first rule, then we have to skip second.
So how many cells?
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
So how many cells we have to skip?
So first of all, the value of.
So this is actually true.
So you have to skip torus.
So this is, first of all, that you have to say this is the second law that you have to skip and then
you have to skip one column.
So two rules plus one column.
And how many elements, how many cells are present in the rules?
So in one rule, there are five elements, five cents.
So two the five plus one.
So basically we have to skip 11 cells.
We have to skip 11 cents and we have to insert our element into Quetzal, so we will we will insert
seven inside.
Well, to sell.
Now that Dalziell will be present at the next eleven, so at index eleven, because the indexing starts
from zero, so that 12th is actually index eleven in one dimension.
So you will store seven at index eleven of this.
So actually, what happens so this calculation, so this calculation, we will not do this calculation,
this calculation is actually automatically done by our system.
So internally, our toread internally, our Julietta is actually going to be stored in the room with
our form, basically only one.
And this calculation, the calculation of finding the correct index.
So this is going to be done by our system automatically.
Can we generate the formula so, for example, I want to insert that I excel and a great column.
So what is what will be our formula?
So here we can see.
If the value of so this is actually a.
And this is actually Jay.
So so we have to insert at index 11, so for finding the 11, what would you multiply to what is two?
Two is a so you will multiply with how many cells are present in one room.
So five other cells present in one room.
Basically, these are the columns.
So these are the columns.
And what is the value of column.
So let's see.
So are the nodes, Ruth.
And see the notes column, so I multiply.
And then basically this plus one is actually the value of.
So you will add plushy.
So this is the formula for calculating the index.
So just let us take an example.
So let's say you want to insert at.
Three.
Komada.
So according to this one.
After all, this is three and this is two, so let's say you want to insert element did now let us use
this formula so the value of it is two.
So this is your eye and this is your job.
So three, multiply.
How many columns are there?
So you can see there are five columns.
So that's why I told you the value of column is mandatory.
Rules are not mandatory because in the formula column will be getting column is getting used, not rules.
So there are five columns.
And what is the value of Jayco?
So the value of JASTA.
So according to this formula you should insert what elements of three to five, fifteen plus two.
You should insert the element at index 17.
So let's say this is your index at 17 and here you will store the element eight.
Now let's see with that.
Our output is whether this formula is correct or wrong.
So skip one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15,
16, 17 and 18.
So basically, you have to skip 17 cents.
So how many cells we have to skip?
We have to skip 17 cells.
That means I want to insert at PNL.
And in the area, the indexing starts from zero, so it means the index is going to be seventeen.
So this is the formula and you have to remember this formula.
So finally so finally, this is I am writing the result for you if you are creating an eddy.
The number of rose are the number of columns Arcy, so a number of rules are denoted by capital letters
and number of columns signed in order by capital letters C.
And if you want to insert if you want to access it raw and get column, so the formula for finding the
correct index is actually a minus, I multiply.
So this is a multiple C plus G.
This is a major.
So what is the formula in Oddisee number of rules sees the number of columns you want to access at Rule
Gate column.
So this is nothing.
This is just I will get multiplied with the columns.
Disvalue.
And you will plushy.
So this is for all media and all the computers users through media.
So if you want to find out the formula for media, what you will do, you will just write the opposite.
Basically interchange, RNC and interchange and simple, just everything will become Abbasid.
So Romeijn is not important.
Our system stored the data in Romijn form.
So that's why this formula is important.
And that's why I told you the value of column is mandatory.
Viterelli of column is mandatory.
So even if you will not give the value of our so you are not giving the value of our letter.
When you are initializing the array you are not giving the value of are not in order to access it through
and yet column.
What do you need.
You need only the value of C.
You can see in this formula R is not used, you only need the value of C, so that's why the value of
C is mandatory.
You have to give value of C so that so that system can use this formula.
So that's why the value is important.
That's why it's mandatory and similarly.
So you can see here what we are doing.
So let's say.
We do not initialize the.
So let's say I'm creating an.
So this is.
Let's say the column surrendered and let's say the rules are five five rules and.
And let us take input from the user only.
So what we are doing here and now, let us call Brent at a function.
Now, if you remember, I told you that whenever you are passing a toread as input to a function, you
have to pass the number of columns.
So here the name of the array is actually.
You will give them and you will give an.
So what we are doing here?
So what we have to do here, so if you remember that I told you that whenever you want to pass a duty
to a function, you have to give a number of columns, not the number of rules, number of rules.
That option number of columns are mandatory.
So I'm creating an array of five rows and columns then the value of his input.
I am taking that as input that I'm calling the function print that I'm giving and adding so many are
correct.
But here what you are doing, you are writing H.I.G..
And what is the formula for AIG, so the formula is I multiply columns plus G.
Now my question is how this function will be able to find the value of C, C, the number of columns.
So there is no way that this function can find out the value of C.
So what we have to do, we have to pass the value of the and how we will pass.
So this is C C is actually handled, so you have to pass.
So that's why you have to write under here.
So it was a letter five.
Now you have to write under there.
That's why I told you that whenever you are passing your duty at it as input to a function, the value
of the rule are optional.
You give or do not give, it is your choice, but the value of columns.
Have to be given, so you have to give the number of columns and this should match these two values
should match 100 and Hender, then only this formula is valid.
Then only we will be able to find out the correct index, so if you will pass it here, then she will
become Hundert.
So that's why whenever I always remember, the value of column is very, very important.
So that's why you have to write under there.
I hope I am clear to you.
And all of this is valid because.
Other systems stole our daughter in law media reform, this is your one lady, so your daughter will
actually will be stored in this one.
The first the first one will get stored.
So first we'll come here, then second, then third row will come, then footrot will come, then we
will come, then six will come and so on.
So for me, this is the formula.
And I hope you can remember this from last remembering this family is really important, and I hope
you guys know that while we have to pass the value of columns to the function and why we have to give
the value of columns when you are creating a delivery because of this formula.
And because of how to react is I actually been told how to react if they're actually getting stored
in our system memory.
So if you have any doubt in this concept, you can definitely ask.
I will see in the next video by.